## JOHN JANG

#### **Product Designer**

+1 647 553 3499

jscolbe9675@gmail.com

My portfolio

#### **SUMMARY**

A York University Grad Product Designer with 1+ year of professional experience in crafting user experience that suits the branding and 1 year of enriched level of experience in web development. I am proficient in designing products from scratch till the launch, while considering the development perspective such as the User Interface development, CI/CD pipeline, deployment, etc. My strengths include strategic designing, initiating projects, and leading communications with internal and external teams. By nature, I am analytical, perceptive, and enjoy problem-solving. Outside of work, I am a runner, dancer, and a potential traveler.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## Product Designer

**OperateEase** 

08 / 2024 ~ Present | Remote, Toronto

- Report to Lead Product Designer and participated weekly UX workshops
- Developed inventory management system for room occupancy and food/beverage supply controls to optimize the operation to 60%

# Product Designer Intern The Sakhi

06 / 2024  $\sim$  10 / 2024 | Remote, Toronto

- Developed and crafted new shopping experience with Indian products and reached the click-through rate of 3.5% as the initial kick-off
- Liaise with Shopify developers to conduct design critique sessions
- Optimized shopping experience by identifying 8 pain points, incorporating user insights, and business requirements

#### **UX** Designer

#### **TuGo Travel**

03 / 2024 ~ 05 / 2024 | Remote, Toronto

 Improved the average engagement time to 10 minutes by simplifying and optimizing exploration and payment process

#### UX/UI Design Apprentice

#### **TeleVU Innovation**

06 / 2022 ~ 08 / 2022 | Remote, Toronto

- Collaborated with colleagues to plan & conduct a research study, gathering insights from 30 participants, to characterize ideal video conference experience
- Redesigned video-call service and increased the rate of use to 80% and average duration of the call to 60%

#### **VOLUNTEER**

# Web Development Apprentice Tech Fleet Professional Association

08 / 2023 ~ 09 / 2024 | Remote, Toronto

- Participated in 4 different web development projects that ranges from social services to blockchain, both web and mobile development
- Collaborated with UX Designers and built applications that are user-friendly

#### UX/UI Design Apprentice

**Tech Fleet Professional Association** 

04 / 2023 ~ 07 / 2023 | Remote, Toronto

 Developed and implemented a user-friendly search functionality based on location and availability that serves
 5,000+ users per month

#### **EDUCATION**

## UX Design

**York University** 

North York, Ontario

#### Web Development Bootcamp

**Dream Coding Academy** September 2022 ~ July 2023 Remote, Toronto

## Psychology & Neuroscience

University of New Brunswick September 2013 ~ June 2017

Fredericton, NB

#### **TOOLS & SKILLS**

Figma, Figjam, Miro, Wireframing, Sketching, Typography, Prototyping, Mock-ups, A/B Testing, Usability Testing Waterfall, User-Interface Design, User Research HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, TypeScript, Next.js, React, Vite, MongoDB, Express.js, Axios

#### OTHER LINKS

LinkedIn - John Jang

**My Web Development Portfolio** 

**Mv Github Profile** 

#### OTHER INFO

Portfolio password: portfolio